Guide to the American Left Ephemera Collection, 1875-2015 AIS.2007.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Other Radical/Leftist Organizations, XIII.
  - "The A B C of Socialism" Leo Huberman and Sybil H. May, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - "Making Patients Pay More" Sam Baker, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - "Resolution and Petition of the Impeachment of Richard Nixon" ACLU Michigan, October 1973 (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - "A United Front Against Fascism", March 1933 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - "People United for Environmental Justice Grassroots Convention Songbook" Citizens' Clearinghouse for Hazardous Waste, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - "Report on the Community Defense project on Organized Neo-fascists in Portland, Oregon" Coalition for Human Dignity, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - "Your Career and Nuclear Weapons" Santa Barbara Peace Group, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - Progressive World vol. 37 no. 3, May- June 1980 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - "Shutdown Strategies Citizen Efforts to Close Nuclear Powerplants" Joseph Kreisburg, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - ACLU New Member's Kit, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - The Roots and Prospects of McCarthyism (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - The Daily Compass vol. 1 no.1, May 1949 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Free Economy vol. VIII no. 10, November 1938 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - The Nation vol. CXVIII no. 3073, May 1924 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Free University Press, University of Pittsburgh (4 issues), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - "Thousands of Children are Hungry" (2 Copies) Illustrated Flyer, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - La Follette's Magazine Vol. XVII No. 1, January 1925 (Box 32, Folder 16a)
  - La Follette's Magazine Vol. XVII No. 2, February 1925 (Box 32, Folder 16b)
  - The Forty Niner vol. XXI no. 49, California State College Student Newspaper, December 1969 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Epic News vol. 1 no. 45, April 1935 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Rally No Nukes, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - "March for Peace and Justice" Poster, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - McGovern-Shriver Campaign Poster, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - American Working Class History Project Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 165)
  - Science & Society Mail Order, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 166)
  - "Unknown Secrets: Art and the Rosenberg Era" Mail Order (Box 37, Folder 167)
  - "Indroducing Color Adjusment" Mail Order, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 168)
  - "Crisis Bargaining" Mail Order (Box 37, Folder 169)
  - "With Babies and Banners: Story of the Women's Emergency Brigade" Mail Order, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 170)
  - Icarus Films Mailing, September 1980 (Box 37, Folder 171)
  - Bread and Roses Mail Order (Box 37, Folder 172)
  - Labor Film Library Flyer (Box 37, Folder 173)
  - Icarus Films Labor Film Library Papers (Box 37, Folder 174)
  - Bread and Roses Order Form (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Monthly Review Press, Spring 1998 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Monthly Review Press, Winter 2000 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Lovestonites
    In 1929 the CPUSA expelled former Party General Secretary Jay Lovestone and a substantial group of followers including Benjamin Gitlow, the CP'S 1924 and 1928 VP candidate. The Lovestone group supported the Soviet faction aligned with Nicholai Bukharin and opposed Comintern Third Period polices which they considered (correctly) sectarian and impractical. Initially the Lovestone group considered itself a loyal opposition to the officially recognized leadership of the CPUSA, but gradually developed a separate organizational identity. Although the group's membership never exceeded a few hundred, it had more influence than might be expected both because officials in several unions respected the advice of prominent Lovestoneites and because the group included several important public intellectuals. Lovestone went on to a career as an activist against Communist influence in the labor movement, both domestic and foreign, and an advisor to portions of the U.S. national security apparatus concerned about that issue.
    - "Marx and America" by Bertram Wolfe, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "The Crisis in the Communist Party, U.S.A", Statement of the Principles of the Communist Party (Majority Group), February, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Pro-War Communism", By Veritas, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Popular Front Culture, XIV.
  The Popular Front grew out of the mutual recognition of Communists and non-Communist leftists in the mid-1930s that they needed to join forces against the threat of fascism. Formalization of this recognition included the 1935 shift in the Comintern line from Third Period policies that had mandated that Communists attack others on the Left as "social fascists" to Popular Front policies for a united front of the Left, and the electoral alliances that led to victories in 1936 elections in France and Spain.
  In the US, the Popular Front functioned like the left wing of the New Deal. It drew support disproportionately from ethnics and racial minorities—e.g. immigrants and their children of Eastern and Southern European heritage, especially Eastern European Jews, and African Americans and Mexican-Americans. Popular Fronters championed the CIO, supported the Spanish Republic and the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, and campaigned for racial equality. It was also a cultural movement as well as a political movement featuring a left-patriotic ethos and a set of stylistic preferences including topical songs in a folk motif, populist paintings inspired by the example of the Mexican muralists, agit-prop Brechtian theater, and social realist literature. A startling array of cultural producers who were either already famous or would later become so participated in Popular Front culture.
  - From These Honored Dead..., By David McKelvy White and James Hawthorne (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of Aiding State Trooper Michael Murray as He Lies on the Ground, September 4, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Wendell Phillips, By James J. Green, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Poems for Workers, An Anthology, Edited by Manuel Gomez (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Ajut Infantil De Reraguarda" Flyer (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "One Year of the Writers and Artists Committee for Medical Aid to Spain" Pamphlet, January-December, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Marxism and Culture No. I", A Brief Bibliography of Marxism and the Arts, Edited by Louis Harp (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hear...Ludwig Renn, Chief of Staff of International Brigades, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Medical Bureau & North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy Flyers (2) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 20 Years After, 1914-1934, By James Lerner (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Critics Group Dialectics #1" Pamphlet, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Issues #2, #4 and #5 of Critics Group Dialectics Stories (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - The Brave and the Blind, A One-Act Drama, By Michael Blankfort, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Issues #3, #6 and #10 of Partisan Review, November-December, 1953,Summer, 1955, and October, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Washington and Lincoln, The American Tradition, By Joseph North (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Photograph of Men from The New York State Young Communist League Boycotting Japanese Goods (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Big Barn Dance" flyer, September 1940 (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - "Front Populaire Revue" Flyer/playbill, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - New Years Evening Dance Flyer (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - "Labor and Culture", Fall 1941 (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - First Hand reports from the Writer's Congress flyer, May 1935 (Box 24, Folder 55)
  - Marching Feet flyer, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 56)
  - May First Celebration program, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 57)
  - Meet the Cast of "Awake and Sing" Clifford Odets flyer, May 1936 (Box 24, Folder 58)
  - Theatre Workshop, October- December 1936 (Box 24, Folder 59)
  - "We Gather Strength", 1933 (Box 24, Folder 60)
  - "Poems" Kenneth Fearing, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 61)
  - Dialectics. 5 issues: 3, 4, 6-8, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 62)
  - Sing Out!, September 1952 (Box 24, Folder 63)
  - People's Songs, December 1946 (Box 24, Folder 64)
  - People's Songs, February-March 1947 (Box 24, Folder 65)
  - Federal Theater Project small archive, 1936-1938 (Box 24, Folder 66)
  - Bay Region Symphony Orchestra Concert postcard, July 1938 (Box 24, Folder 67)
  - "Stop Barbaric Slaughter with a Human Boycott" press photo, January, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 68)
  - The New Anvil, April/May 1939 (Box 24, Folder 69)
  - Songs of Joe Hill, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 70)
  - New Masses, December 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - New Masses, May 1947 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - New Masses. 6 issues, 1935-1946 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 1 No. 2, April/May 1934 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 2 No. 7, April/May 1935 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 2 No. 8, July/August 1935 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 13 No. 3, Vol. 4 No. 1-2, Summer 1946- March/April 1947 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 14 No. 3-4, Vol. 15 No. 1, May/June 1947- January 1948 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 15 No. 2-4, February 1948- April 1948 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 15 No. 5-6, 8, May 1948- August 1948 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 15 No. 12, Vol. 16 No. 1, 4, December 1948- April 1949 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Partisan Review, Vol. 16 No. 6, 10-11, June 1949- November 1949 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Legal Briefs from suits by blacklisted Hollywood screenwriters, actor and directors against Hollywood Studios (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Play Bureau, December 1936 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - New Theatre, June 1935 (Box 33, Folder 2A)
  - New Theatre, August 1935 (Box 33, Folder 2B)
  - New Theatre, June 1936 (Box 33, Folder 2C)
  - New Theatre, November 1936 (Box 33, Folder 2D)
- Progressive Party, XV.
  Former Vice President Henry Wallace ran for President on a third party Progressive ticket in 1948. The Progressive Party emphasized three themes: opposition to Cold War policies, expansion of New Deal reform towards something closer to European social democracy, and racial equality. Serious discussion of a possible left third party began in 1946. In its earliest stages this movement drew support from a broad array of New Dealers, officials and activists in state third parties such as the New York American Labor Party, the Minnesota Farmer Labor Party, or the Washington Commonwealth Federation (more of a faction in the Washington State Democratic Party than a third party), CIO officials, and left-wing intellectuals.
  The Communists, at first, were not enthusiastic both because the Progressive Party might be a competitor on the Left and because the international Communist line was shifting toward a more sectarian posture less welcoming of united fronts. But, as the Cold War heated up, the Progressives' anti-Cold War posture caused the CP to shift toward enthusiastic support for the Progressive Party. However, the CP's active engagement with the Progressive Party undermined much of its non-Communist support. Wallace's disappointing 1948 popular vote--barely more than 2% after initial projections of perhaps 10 to 20%--further discouraged those non-Communists who had stuck with the organization. The Party faltered on through the 1952 campaign, but was justifiably viewed by most non-Communist observers as little more than a Communist front.
  - "We Propose this Program of Peace and Abundance for the People of North Carolina" Pamphlet, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - IPP Record (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Draft Platform Progressive Party of North Carolina, April 25 1948; 3 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Progressive Party Platform, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Public Affairs Pamphlet No. 1, A Program For Jobs In N.Y. State", Issued By Council on Public Affairs, N.Y. State American Labor Party (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "Could Peace Cost So Much?" Flyer, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "The Other Evil", The Truth About the 1952 Elections, By Vito Marcantonio (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "He Thinks Right" (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Flyer Discussing Police Brutality in Detroit, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Tribune Record, April 17, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Flyer for The Progressive Party of Delaware (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "We Can Have Homes" (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "The Third Party and the 1948 Elections", By Eugene Dennis, March, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - A Flyer from the Young Progressives of Ohio (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "The 3rd Party", By Adam Lapin (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Flyer Encouraging People to Vote for the Progressive Party (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "The Outlook for the N.Y. City Elections", By Simon W. Gerson (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - "Speak up for Peace" (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Flyer to Vote for Henry Steinberg (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - "YOU Can Stop the Korean War YOU Can Stop World War 3 With a VOTE" Flyer, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - "Fed Up..." Flyer, ca. 1938 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Progressive Party of Philadelphia Letter, November 17, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - "Knock on Any Door!", Progressive Party (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Pamphlet to Elect Progressive Party Candidate Mrs. Charlotta Bass (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - "Your Vote Can Stop the War in Korea Now!" Pamphlet (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - "Vote for Wallace" Flyer (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - "Red Herring" Flyer, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Progressive Party Campaign Items (5), 1948 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "How Your Congressman Voted On:" Intro by Henry A Wallace, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Socialist Labor Party (SLP), XVI.
  The Socialist Labor Party began in 1876 as the Workingmen's Party of the United States, renamed the Socialistic Labor Party in 1877. A tiny remnant survives today.
  Its only notable successes occurred in the years immediately after the 1877 railroad strike near the end of the bitter 1870s depression. The railroad strike had been as much a popular insurrection as a conventional strike. Fueled both by the anger that had provoked this insurrection and the sense of empowerment that it had kindled, significant numbers of U.S. workers turned to third party protest voting between 1877 and 1880. Most of those protest votes went to the Greenback-Labor Party, but the SLP drew substantial votes and elected local officials and state legislators in many Midwestern cities with substantial German immigrant populations.
  The Party faded badly in the early 1880s because of a split between Marxists and anarchists, an upswing in the economy, and the rise of the Knights of Labor, a more credible organizational home for working-class activists than the SLP. In the early 1890s a charismatic intellectual, Daniel De Leon, took over leadership of what was left of the party. Although De Leon was an original thinker—Lenin praised him as the only American to make noteworthy contribution to Marxist theory—he was a terrible organizer, so irascible and dogmatic that he repeatedly drove people away from the organization.
  Despite De Leon's flaws the Party expanded in the 1890s benefitting from another Depression beginning in 1893, the surge of political energy accompanying the Populist movement, and publicity surrounding the announcement that railroad union leader Eugene Debs had converted to socialism. Inevitably, however, these new recruits came into conflict with the De Leonites. They joined with other socialist factions to found the Socialist Party of the United States (SPUSA) in 1901. The new party quickly eclipsed the SLP.
  De Leon and his followers had one more story to tell. They played a key role on the founding of the IWW (Industrial Workers of the World) in 1905. Inevitably De Leon had a falling out with others in the IWW leadership, and left the organization to form a rival IWW faction in 1908.
  - "1940 Platform...No Peace Without Socialism!" (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - "Karl Marx, The Man and His Work and the Constructive Elements of Socialism", Three Lectures and Two Essays By Karl Dannenberg, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - "Socialist Reconstruction of Society", The Industrial Vote, By Daniel De Leon (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Grand March Festival Given By The Socialists of St. Paul, Minn. at Germania Turner Hall, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - A Socialist Labor Party Envelope and Ticket (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Three Letters to Sections and Members of the S.L.P., February 23 and 27, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - "Economic Basis of Education", By Aaron M. Orange, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - "A Socialist Labor Party Statement, What Can Be Done About Unemployment?" (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - "The Fetishism of Liberty", By Harry Waton, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - "From Reform to Bayonets", By Arnold Petersen, May, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Multiple Socialist Labor Party Documents Addressed to Samuel Johnson (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - "Anti-Semitism, Its Cause and Cure Daniel de Leon", 1921 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - "Socialism: World Without Race Prejudice", By Eric Hass (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - "Unionism: Fraudulent of Genuine?", By Nathan Karp, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - "Democracy", Past, Present and Future, By Arnold Petersen, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - 1964 Platform or the Socialist Labor Party of America (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - "Discussion Bulletin", February, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Flyer for a Musical and Lecture (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - "Socialist Album", 1896 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Christmas Entertainment Newsletter, December 27 1896 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - "Winter Evening Agitation Meetings" leaflet, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - "Vote for the Socialist Labor Party" Flyer (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Socialist Labor Party Flyers, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - SLP Section St. Louis Grievance Committee Meeting, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - The People's Library vol. 1 no. 2, January 1899 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The People's Library vol. 1 no. 4, July 1899 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Tragic Pages from the History of Strikes among the Miners, September 1900 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - GEO E. Lawrence TLS (2) and Flyer, 1892 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Bound Group of Socialist Pamphlets, Socialist Labor Party (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "A Philosophy of Happiness" Thomas Bersford, October 1899 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - "The Gospel of Discontent" G.B. Benham, September 1897 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - "Forging of the New: Studies in Socialism" Fanklin H. Wentworth, 1907 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "Civilization Civilized" Stephen Maybell, November 1895 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - "Scientific Socialism" Thomas Bersford, July 1899 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - "The Crimes of Capitalism" G.B. Benham, January 1898 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - "Patriotism and Socialism" G.B. Benham, June 1899 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - "The Story of the Red Flag" G. B. Benham, 1897 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - "The Attitude of the Socialists Toward Trade Unions", 1900 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - "Gov. Altgeld's Pardon & The Modern Tragedy: Downfall of the Small Producer & The Crisis", June 1894 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - "Catechism of Socialism" G. B. Benham, March 1898 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Bulletin of the Social Labor Movement, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - 1904 Ticket for Ball (St. Paul, Minn.) (Box 39, Folder 17)
- Socialist Party USA (SPUSA), XVII.
  Founded in 1901 by disgruntled members of the Socialist Labor Party and other Socialist factions, the party became the most electorally successful left-wing party in US history. It reached a peak membership of almost 120,000 in 1912 and again in 1919, and drew about 3% of the national popular vote in the elections of 1904, 1908, 1916, and 1920 and 6% in 1912. During these years the Party elected congressmen from New York City and Milwaukee, several dozen state legislators and perhaps as many as a thousand local officials including mayors of such major cities as Milwaukee and Minneapolis.
  As a result of the 1919 split within their ranks between the Party's Old Guard and those that wanted the Party to join the emerging Communist movement and the effects of government repression, the Socialist Party collapsed in the early 1920s. The Party endorsed Progressive Party candidate Robert La Follette in the 1924 presidential campaign and that endorsement masked the Party's weakness. La Follette drew nearly 17% of the national popular vote. Moreover La Follette had failed to achieve Progressive Party ballot status in several large states and only appeared there as a Socialist. Socialists could thus claim enough of the La Follette vote as their own to argue that their 1924 totals compared favorably to the percentages they had received between 1904 and 1920. But in 1928 when Norman Thomas made the first of his six presidential runs the Socialist vote was down to 0.7%.
  The depression appeared to revive the Socialist Party in the early 1930s. Thomas expanded his presidential vote percentage to 2.2% in 1932, and in 1934 the Party elected mayors in Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Bridgeport, Connecticut; and Reading, Pennsylvania. Thereafter the Party found itself caught between a rapidly expanding Communist Party on one side and a Democratic Party that shifted to the Left after 1934. A substantial portion of the Party membership and leadership, including David Dubinsky and Sidney Hillman, leaders of International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union (ACWU), two of the Party's bastions, argued that Socialists should endorse FDR in 1936. When the top Party leadership refused to consider this, they seceded forming a rival Social Democratic Federation that did endorse Roosevelt. Thomas's vote fell to 0.4% in 1936. The Party continued to run candidates thereafter—up to the present—but rarely did much better than other tiny left-wing factions such as the Socialist Labor Party (SLP) or the Socialist Workers Party (SWP).
  - "Which Road for American Workers, Socialist or Communist?", January, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Assorted Socialist Party-Social Democratic Convention Papers (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - "Public Ownership Here and Abroad", By Harry W. Laidler, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - "An Appeal to the Young", By P. Kropotkin (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - The Melting Pot, Home Again With the Melting Pot, June, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - "The Germs of War", A Study in Preparedness, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - "Letters to Judd", An American Workingman, By Upton Sinclair (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - "Think or Surrender", By George R. Kirkpatrick (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Assorted Writings (5) By Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - "Two Constitutions", By Oscar Ameringer (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Assorted Leftist Papers (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - "Sit-Down", By Joel Seidman, and "A G.M. Stockholder Visits Flint", By Robert Morss Lovett, March, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - "Realignment", One Year After the Party Convention (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - "The Appeal Almanac and Arsenal of Facts for 1917" (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - "No!,Steps to Create Peace", By the Peace Work Group Socialist Party USA (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - "America at the Crossroads", By David P. Berenberg, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - "Leaflet No. 6", Testimony to the Charges Against Assemblyman Solomon (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - "Tampa- Tar and Terror" (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - "Wages in Mexican Money", By Mary E. Marcy (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - "Socialist Campaign Songs" (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - "Socialist Song Book" (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - "Value, Price and Profit", By Karl Marx (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Intemperance and Poverty, by T. Twining (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Pocket Library of Socialism, No. 39, "Socialism and the Organized Labor Movement", By May Wood Simmons (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Pocket Library of Socialism, No. 48, "Useful Work Versus Useless Toil", By William Morris (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Pocket Library of Socialism, No. 50, "Marx on Cheapness" (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - "Economic Evolution", By Paul Lafargue (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - "Science and Socialism", By Robert Rives La Monte (Box 10, Folder 89)